[Music]
Hi, my name is Angus and I'm the inventor of the Kangaroo Hanger, which is essentially a big paper
clip for your clothes.
It clips in everything in your closet.
It's made with 100% recycled materials in Wisconsin.
Today I want to tell you about my experience with brand ownership and brand protection on Amazon.
I've heard a lot of horror stories about brands getting ripped off, so I do everything I can to
protect my brand Kangaroo.
And it's especially important on Amazon.
The way I protect my brand Kangaroo on Amazon is I patented the design.
So I have a registered patent, and I have multiple trademarks for the Kangaroo name internationally.
Amazon has evolved a lot to help brands protect their intellectual property.
I don't really feel like you have to worry very much on Amazon because of how easy it is to get
people who are knocking you off, shut down, or get their listings removed.
All you have to do is register your brand's trademark, and when you go to the Amazon brand registry
portal, you can actually do an image search by uploading an image of your product,
and it will look through Amazon's entire database of listings for stuff that looks similar.
And then you can checkbox every single item that may be someone infringing on your product or someone
completely copying it.
You can essentially flag all of those at once for infringement, whether that's on your trademark
or on your patent.
And generally stuff that's actually infringing on your product or your trademark will get taken
down within a day or two.
So that's why I feel like I don't really have to worry too much about my brand on Amazon.
As long as I have my trademarks, my patents, protecting the product.
Once you put in your pending or approved trademarks, you can actually create a brand store on Amazon.
So when a customer's on your listing, they'll see at the top of your brand name, and it's a little
link.
And when they click on that, that will bring them to your brand page, which is essentially like
a website that you can create for customers to shop all of your products.
And if you ever need hangers, check out the Kangaroo Hanger.